hey guys welcome to this rotation video
we're gonna rotate this figure by 270
degrees these this way to do rotations
in my opinion is using the notes these
are notes for the different rotations
we're gonna use the one for 270 degrees
so first step we want to write down the
3 points of our preimage the 3 points of
the image that we're given it's a
negative 3 to negative 6 2 and negative
3 9 they were going to apply the
transformation given to us from above so
for 270 it says list the Y so we're
switching them so we're gonna take the Y
value and put it in the X spot so I took
the Y from here and put it into X 4
there then it says do negative X or
whatever the opposite of the first one
is now going to become our new second
one so the negative negative 3 becomes 3
this becomes a positive 6 this becomes a
positive 3 now we just plot the points
that we just mapped into so 2 3 2 6 and
9 3 then we're gonna connect the dots
and now you can see that the figure was
rotated 270 degrees so change the
orientation and the quadrant that it's
in so this makes sense if not have a
link down below 2 more practice in
videos and problems on Andy math com
feel free to check it out please like
this video and subscribe to my channel
now sod you guys soon
[Music]